星际之门亚特兰帝斯
前情提要
Previously on Stargate Atlantis
Ara Rakai
ara, rakai.
哦 耶!
Oh yeah!
我 Raikai和Ara 都是你的朋友
Me, rakai, ara, we're your friends.
你应该和我们在一起
You belong with us.
你们想要袭击一个Wraith实验室?
You want to hit a wraith lab?
如果有一艘飞船的话
我们就能在增援赶到之前
Having a ship would make things a whole lot easier getting us in and out
全身而退
before any reinforcements arrive.
我们走这边 你们走哪边
We'll go this way. You go that way.
找到什么的话就联系我们
Contact us if you find anything.
哦 是你们三个 谢天谢地
Oh, oh, thank god it's you three.
你们是Wraith崇拜者...
它们给你们什么了?
The wraith worshipers-- they did you.
他们赋予了我们永恒的生命
They rewarded us with the gift of everlasting life.
- Rakai 不要!
- 不准使用武器
- Rakai, no!
- No weapons.
Rodney 尽可能躲得远一点
因为我们下次再见的时候
Rodney, get away while you can, because the next time we meet,
就不是朋友了
it will not be as friends.
你最近几天睡着了吗?
You getting any sleep these days?
恐怕没有
Not much, I'm afraid.
但是Kanaan被允许从大陆回归以后
情况已经好多了
Although things are a little easier now that kanaan's request has been granted and he's been allowed to return from the mainland.
他喜欢大城市中的生活吗?
How's he liking life in the big city?
他很乐意能和Torren和我团聚
Well, he's happy to be reunited with torren and I,
但是要适应Atlantis上的生活有些困难
but he's having difficulty adjusting to life on atlantis.
嗯 我听说淋浴把他给吓坏了
Yeah, I hear the shower scared him.
在你的生日惊喜派对上
你还把Gero博士给击昏了呢
And you once stunned dr. Gero at your own surprise birthday party.
他吓到我了
He spooked me.
啊哈
Uh-huh.
反正这对Kanaan来说很困难
It's difficult for kanaan.
当然 他有我和Torren 但是...
He has torren and me, of course, but
我还是觉得他很孤独
I still think he feels isolated.
嗯 他需要交一些新朋友
Yeah, well, he just needs to make some new friends.
你应该叫他有空到健身房来玩玩
You should get him to come by the gym sometime.
我们可以练练拳击
We could spar.
谢谢你的好意 但是在一段时间内
我不希望他缺胳膊少腿
Thank you. That's very kind of you, but I need him in one piece for the foreseeable future.
啊 你太无趣了
Ah, you're no fun.
嘿!
hey!
Ronon!
Tyre
Tyre.
星际之门 亚特兰蒂斯
第5季 第3集
Stargate Atlantis
Season 05 Episode 03
Daedalus号已经确认了
你们初步搜索的结果
The daedalus confirms the results of your preliminary search.
那个星球上没有Ronon
皮下追踪器的信号
There's no sign of ronon's subcutaneous transmitter anywhere on that planet.
心结
Broken Ties
这就意味着他还活着
That means he's still alive.
如果Tyre只想杀了他
我们应该能找到尸体了
If tyre wanted him dead, we would have found the body.
除非他把Ronon带到了什么地方慢慢折磨
Unless he just took him somewhere to exact a slow revenge.
我不想说的太消极
I don't mean to sound overly negative,
但是我听说他的思想已经很扭曲了
but from what I've heard, his mind is seriously warped.
但是他没有杀我
And yet he didn't kill me.
杀光目击者应该对他来说更安全些
It would have been safer for him to leave no witnesses.
那么 虽然Wraith对他进行了改造
So perhaps, despite what the wraith did to him,
但可能他还保留着Satedan人的荣誉感
tyre still possesses his satedan sense of honor.
但这并没有阻止他埋伏你们
It didn't stop him from ambushing you.
也许我们可以利用Satedan人的荣誉感
来帮助我们找Ronon
Maybe we can use that satedan sense of honor to help us find ronon.
你准备怎么做?
How do you propose we do that?
我们得找一个Satedan人来帮我们
We get a satedan to help us.
你不会正巧认识一个吧?
You happen to have one handy, do you?
Teyla知道在哪能找到
Teyla knows where one is.
Solen Sincha
Solen sincha.
谁?
Who?
他是Wraith攻击Sateda后的幸存者
He is a survivor of the wraith attack on sateda.
两年前我和Ronon
在Belkan执行交易任务时碰到过他
Ronon and i encountered him on a trade mission to belkan two years ago.
根据你的描述
他不太像会呆在一个地方的人
By your description, he isn't exactly the settle-down kind of guy.
有多大可能他还在那呢?
What are the chances he's still there?
实践是检验真理的唯一标准咯
There's only one way to find out.
Woolsey先生 我们请求进行星际旅行
Mr.Woolsey, permission to go off-world?
- 批准
- 太好了
- You have a go.
- Great.
哦 还有 Teyla
Oh, and teyla,
你会和Sheppard中校
和McKay博士一起去吗?
will you be accompanying colonel sheppard and dr. Mckay?
我还没有正式收到你的复职请求
所以问一下
I only ask because I've yet to receive your formal request to return to active duty.
她当然会归队了 是吧?
Of course she'll be returning. Right?
我还没有决定是否归队
I'm yet to make a decision about my future with the team.
哦
Oh.
好吧
Okay.
但是我还是会和中校博士一起去Belkan
However, I would still like to accompany colonel sheppard and dr. Mckay to belkan.
当然
Of course.
Teyla!
Teyla去哪了?
Where's teyla?
我把她留在那个星球上面了
I left her back on the planet.
别担心 她很好
Don't worry. She's fine.
你知道我不会伤害她的
You know I wouldn't hurt her.
我不知道
Do I?
我知道你不再相信我了
I accept the fact that you no longer trust me,
但是时间会改变一切
but I'm hoping that will change in time.
Sateda已经毁灭了
Sateda is gone.
我们是最后的Sateda人了
We're the last of our kind, ronon.
我们是兄弟
We're brothers,
不是敌人
not enemies.
我们是兄弟?
We're brothers?
那我是不是应该原谅你
去年给我设套?
So I should just forgive you for setting me up last year?
如果你懂道理的话
事情就不会发展到今天这一步
If you had just listened to reason, things could have been different.
Ara和Rakai就不会死了
Ara and rakai would still be alive,
我们就能团圆了
and we'd all be working together again.
我们要以Wraith崇拜者和叛徒的身份
来纪念Sateda吗?
As wraith worshipers and traitors to the memory of sateda?
不
Hell, no.
当然不是
Of course not.
我懂了
I see that now.
你是被过去蒙蔽了
You're blinded by the past,
被你在Atlantis上那些所谓的朋友
给欺骗了
lied to by your so-called friends on atlantis.
但我还对你有信心 老朋友
But ilst fhaaith in you, old friend.
你需要敞开双臂 拥抱事实
You just need to open your eyes to the truth.
好吧
All right.
给我松绑 我就听听你有什么要说的
Just untie me and I'll listen to what you have to say.
那是在你把我...
Would that be before
打昏之前还是之后?
or after you try to beat me unconscious?
我不知道
I don't know.
你来选
You choose.
或者我可以给你来个突然袭击
Or I could just surprise you.
我不怀疑
I don't doubt it.
你怎么了?
What's wrong with you?
我不太好
I'm not well.
但是我还有更糟的时候
But I've been worse.
你知道我们在哪吗?
You know where we are?
你还记得Sarif Sur吧?
You remember sarif sur, don't you?
嗯 那一次你差点死了
Yeah. You almost died on that run.
我们都差点死掉 就因为你不愿丢下我
We botnearly died because you refused to leave me behind.
你冒着生命危险来救我
You risked your life to save me.
今天...
Today...
我还你这个人情
I return the favor.
Solen Sincha?
Solen sincha.
走开
Go away.
你看不出来我在睡觉吗?
Can't you see I'm trying to sleep?
我么需要你的帮助
We need your help.
Ronon Dex有麻烦了
Ronon dex is in trouble.
Ronon Dex总是有麻烦
Ronon dex is always in trouble.
他有生命危险
Well, his life is in danger.
还有什么新一点的没?
Again. What else is new?
他这次又给自己惹上什么麻烦了?
What kind of trouble has he gotten himself into this time?
他被一个Satedan绑架了
He was abducted by a fellow satedan,
一个名叫Tyre的Wraith崇拜者
a wraith worshiper by the name of tyre.
你是说前Wraith崇拜者
You mean former wraith worshiper.
据说那条狗让它的主人失望了
于是它们把它抛弃了
Word is the dog disappointed his masters, so they turned him loose.
那它们真是难得的仁慈啊
Well, that's uncharacteristically kind of them.
也不尽然
Not exactly.
只要他还在逃 他就是
让Wraith失望的下场的
So long as he's on the run, he's a living, breathing example
活生生的例子
of what happens to humans who disappoint them.
Tyre现在是过街老鼠
Tyre's a marked man now.
我认识的大多数人见他就会杀
只是时间问题了
Most anyone I know would kill him on sight.
It's just a matter of time.
他曾经是一个自豪的Satedan人
和你差不多
He was once a proud satedan, not unlike yourself.
他们对他进行了不可想象的折磨
He was subjected to unimaginable torture.
也许他没有选择
Perhaps he had no choice.
总会有选择的
There's always a choice.
他可以像真正的Satedan一样选择死
He could have chosen death like a true satedan.
知道我们到哪可以找到他吗?
Any idea where we can find him?
如果我知道的话 他就已经死了
If I knew that, he'd already be dead.
好吧 Tyre的脑子不太好使 对吧?
All ght. Tyre's not thinking straight, right?
嗯
Sure.
那么他说漏嘴很有可能只是时间问题
So it's probably just a matter of time before he slips up.
他透露以后 我想你会知道的
And when he does, I'm assuming your leads will hear about it.
有可能
Probably.
那听到风声以后就联系我们
So what do you say, you contact us when you hear something.
我们会处理Tyre 免得劳您大驾
We'll deal with tyre and save you the trip.
好的
All right.
敬Ronon
To ronon.
看看你
Look at you.
你连路都走不了
You can barely walk.
让我帮你吧
Let me get you some help.
你帮不了我
I'm beyond your help.
这是Wraith弄得吧?
It's the wraith, isn't it?
它们对你做了什么?
What did they do to you?
到了这个时候
At this point,
不是它们对我做了什么
而是它们没对我什么
it's not so much what they did to me as what they aren't doing to me.
给你生命吗?
Giving you life?
反向取食什么的?
Reverse-feeding or whatever the hell it's called?
很难形容
It's hard to describe.
那带来的幸福感简直是...
The sense of euphoria it offers is...
你上瘾了
you became addicted to it.
你不试一下的话是不会理解的
You can't understand unless you've experienced it yourself.
那是一个礼物
It was a gift,
但自从我让你和你的朋友逃跑以后
就无法享用了
one that was denied me after I allowed you and your friends to escape us.
嘿
Hey,
放了我 我能找人帮你
free me, and I'll get you some help.
我保证
I promise.
已经有人要来帮我了
Help is already on the way.
帮我们两个
For both of us.
什么意思?
What does that mean?
你做了什么?
What the hell did u do?
我救了我们的命
I've saved us.
Ronon Dex
ronon dex.
我一直期盼着你能为我服务的那一天
I looked forward to the day when you would finally serve me.
很遗憾要让你失望了
Well, then, I'm going to feel real bad disappointing you.
哦 我知道你会努力的
Oh, I'm sure you'll try.
但最终
But, in the end,
你会改变主意
you'll come around.
Woolsey先生
Mr. Woolsey
Teyla
Teyla.
有Ronon的消息吗?
Any news on ronon?
没有
Not yet.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
想一想他的生存能力
我们可以放心一些
I suppose we can draw comfort from the fact that he is a proven survivor.
他做流浪者的时候
和命运搏斗了很多年
He defied the odds for many years as a runner.
是的
Yes, he did.
我能帮你什么吗?
How can I help you?
我想为没有尽早告诉你
我的决定的事道歉
I wanted to apologize for not having come to you sooner with a decision regarding my position on the colonel's team.
你想什么时候告诉我都可以
Take whatever time you need.
如果有必要
If necessary,
我可以有找人顶替你
I can assign someone to fill in for you.
哦
Oh...
Woolsey先生 你有孩子吗?
mr. Woolsey, do you have children?
没有
Uh, no.
不过Yorkie陪了我很多年
But I did have a yorkie for many years.
一只小狗
It's a small dog.
但离婚的时候我妻子把它带走了
But my wife got him in the divorce.
我爱那条狗
I loved that dog.
却连说再见的机会都没有
I never really had the chance to say goodbye.
所以 没有...
So, no.
没有孩子
No children.
那么 你可能理解不了
这对我来说有多么困难
Then, with all due respect, you may not understand how difficult this is for me.
我活到现在
For most of my life,
从没有想过离开我的人民
I never imagined the possibility of leaving my people,
一刻都没有...
not even for a moment...
然后情况发生了变化...
and then circumstances changed.
在了解了我在Sheppard的小队
中的重要性后
And after realizing a far more important role on colonel sheppard's team,
我从没想到该放手的时间已经到了
I never imagined the day would come when I would have to let it go.
那个时间就是现在
And now here that day is.
5年前
Five years ago,
如果有人问我会不会接收一个
银河系外的工作
if anyone had asked me if I ever planned on taking a job outside of the milky way,
我的回答肯定是不
my answer would have been a definite no.
而现在...
And now...
看看我
look at me.
嗯...
So...
虽然我不能和你产生共鸣...
while I can't empathize,
但是我同情你的处境
I certainly do sympathize.
相信我 我知道...
Believe me, I know--
有时候目标是会变的
priorities change.
有的时候不会
And sometimes they don'T.
Teyla 我相信Kanaan会支持你的
Teyla, I'm sure kanaan will support you
不管你作出什么选择
whatever decision you make.
是的 他会的
Yes. Of course he will.
谢谢你 Woolsey先生
Thank you, mr. Woolsey.
生命被偷了的感觉怎么样?
How does it feel to have your life stolen?
离黑暗那么的接近...
To be pushed so close to the darkness,
直到边缘才被拉回来的感觉如何?
only to be pulled back from the brink?
据我所知
From what I understand,
这是很神奇的感觉
it's a magnificent sensation.
老实说
To be honest,
感觉不错
I've felt better.
随便你怎么否认
Defy me all you want.
你们这些Satedan人都是一样的
Your fellow satedans were no different.
和他们一样 你最终会屈服的
Like them, you'll eventually submit.
在那之前我就死了
I'll die before I submit.
不
No.
不会的
You won'T.
嘿
Hey.
你起得好早啊
You're up early.
已经10点了
10:00 A.M.
是吗?
It is?
哦 天那
Oh, god.
我昨晚一点都没睡
I didn't sleep at all. I was up all night
一直在想Ronon的情况
thinking about this ronon situation.
- 想到什么吗?
- 没有 我试过所有的方法...
- Got anything?
- Nothing. I tried everything--
踱步啊 吃东西啊 泡澡啊...
pacing, snacking, bathing--
泡澡?
bathing.
是的
Yeah.
就像阿基米德
Like archimedes.
你指那个喜欢Teyla的希腊科学家?
You mean that greek scientist who had a crush on teyla?
不 我指到发明阿基米德原理
No, like the greek mathematician who came up with the archimedes principle,
也就是浮力定律的希腊数学家
the physical laws of buoyancy.
据传说
According to legend,
他在浴缸里面想到了这个点子
the idea came to him when he was sitting in the bath, so...
关键是他在放松的情况下
想到了这个关系
look, the point is that the revelation occurred while he was relaxing.
他没在想这个问题
He was not thinking about the problem.
而答案却一直在他眼前
And the solution, as it turns out, was right in front of him all along.
你觉得我们忽视了什么东西?
You think we've overlooked something?
我不知道
I don't know.
我整晚都没睡 反复想这件事 却一无所获
Maybe. Look, all I know is I was up all night going over it and I'm drawing a blank,
所以我采取了一个新的视角
so I could use a fresh perspective.
我不是在和你谈洗澡
I'm not taking a bath with you.
我们过一下我们知道的东西吧
Let's just go over what we know.
Solen说 Tyre在逃
According to solen, tyre's on the run.
我们可以假设他是独自行动的
And we can assume he's operating alone because
因为如果他有后援的话
在埋伏的时候应该出现
if he had backup, they would have been in on the ambush.
对 他一个人 带着Ronon 在逃
Right. He's alone, with ronon, on the run.
那么这样的人会到哪去呢?
So where would someone like that go?
我能想到200个无人居住的理想星球
Well, I can think of something like 200 uninhabited planets that would be perfect.
你想从哪开始?
Where do you want to start?
Sarif Sur怎么样?
How about sarif sur?
什么?
What?
我们刚从Ronon的伙计Solen那收到消息
We just got a message from ronon's buddy, solen.
他听说Tyre和Ronon被关在
一个叫Sarif Sur的星球上
He hears that tyre and ronon are holed up on a planet called sarif sur.
谢谢你 阿基米德
Thank you, archimedes.
中校 让你的小队准备出发
Major, get your team and gear up.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
没有什么理由好坚持的
There's just no point in holding on.
你只是在逃避现实
You're just putting off the inevitable.
你接受的话会更好些
It's better if you just accept it.
是对你来说更好些吧?
You mean better for you, don't you?
Wraith不要你了
The wraith cut you off
而你把我当成牺牲品
and this is your way back in,
来重新回到它们的怀抱
by offering me up as a sacrifice.
不
No.
你不是我冒险救出来的人
You're not the man I risked my life for.
你是我们人民的叛徒
You're a traitor to the memory of our people.
不值得他们尊敬
You have no honor.
进展太慢了
Things are progressing too slowly.
我还有其他事要处理
I have other matters to attend to.
我们可以回到实验室进行
We can continue this process back at the lab.
那我什么时候可以得到奖赏?
And when will I receive my reward?
奖赏?
Your reward?
我按照协议把他带来了
I brought him here as we agreed.
作为交换 你答应恢复我们先前的协议
In exchange, you promised to restore our previous arrangement.
呃 有吗?
Huh. Did I?
你承诺过!
You promised!
恐怕我得让你失望了
I'm afraid I'm going to have to disappoint,
没有利用价值的东西
since your usefulness has come to an end.
我们会找到他的
We'll get him.
敬候佳音 中校
See that you do, colonel.
没人
Nothing.
我们搞错了
So we were wrong.
早就知道会这样
It has been known to happen.
嘿 我早就说了这个消息不可靠
Hey, I always said this was a longshot.
中校 我是Lorne
Colonel, this is lorne.
我们发现点情况
We've got something.
我就知道
I knew it.
这里
Over here.
我们检查了他的脉搏
We checked his pulse.
非常微弱 我们得把他抬走
要不然他就没命了
It's barely there. We've got to move him or we lose him.
- Ronon呢?
- 问得好
- Where's ronon?
- Good question.
他的伤势不重
His injuries are minor,  but
但是心率和血压都很高
both his heartrate and blood pressure are elevated.
带他回来后一个小时 他醒过一次
He woke up about an hour after you brought him in.
精神混乱 发汗 恶心呕吐 浑身发抖
He was delirious, he was sweating, nauseous, trembling.
所以我给他注射了镇静剂
然后做了些检查
So I sedated him and ran some tests.
在使用阻塞阿片样物质受体的药物后
After giving him a drug that blocks opioid receptors,
我注意到这个区域的多巴鞍值有所下降
I noticed a drop in dopamine levels here--
这里是大脑的犒赏回路
a central link in the brain's reward circuit.
什么意思?
Right. Meaning?
意味着这种神经化学品所造成的影响
和吸毒者完全一样
Meaning this type of neurochemical activity is identical to that of reforming substance-users.
他正在经历戒毒的过程
He's going through withdrawal.
你一定要救他 医生
I need you to save him, doc.
现在他是我们唯一的希望
如果他挂了 找到Ronon的线索也就没了
Right now, he's our only lead.
If he dies, our chances of finding ronon go with him.
当然 可要想让恢复到足够清醒
并告诉我们一些信息 可能需要些日子
Of course. But it could be days before he's coherent enough to tell us anything.
John!
为什么没通知我参加Ronon的营救任务?
John! Why wasn't I informed about the mission to rescue ronon?
我们是临时决定的 没来得及通知
We were playing on a hunch. We had to act fast.
我先走了 呃 看看午餐准备好了没
I'm going go, um, see if they're still serving lunch.
星期二供应小卷饼
It's taquito tuesday.
我觉得我该和你一起去
I think I'll join you.
我很惊讶你居然丢下我行动
I'm surprised that you would be so quick to move forward without me.
别让我背黑锅
Don't put this on me.
你可以对回归小队这件事改变主意
You're the one having second thoughts about returning to the team.
我不能每次出去探险都让你做选择
I cannot give you the option every time we're going off-world.
这对我来说也不是轻松的选择
This is not an easy decision for me.
你认为你是唯一一个有压力的?
You think you're the only one feeling pressure?
我也被Woolsey逼的很紧
他叫我找一个人代替你
I've got woolsey pushing me hard to find a replacement for you.
那你怎么跟他说的?
What did you tell him?
我告诉他在我和你谈过之前我
不会采取任何行动
I told him that I wasn't going to do anything until I talked to you.
现在 如果你想要加入小分队 很好
Now, if you want to join the team, great.
我通知Woolsey 我去跟他说
I'll call woolsey. I'll make it happen.
但是如果你想要花时间陪儿子的话
我理解 真的 我真的理解
But if you want to spend time with your son, I understand. I do. I really do.
你得做出取舍
You've got to make a decision.
你终于醒了
You're finally awake.
过程会很辛苦
The procedure can be very taxing.
大部分时间你会失去意识
You've been unconscious for the better part of a day.
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
在我转变前我会先死掉
I'll die before I turn.
就像Marika和Hemi一样
Just like marika and hemi.
恐怕你弄错了
I'm afraid you're mistaken.
你的朋友并不是因为太强壮而死掉的
Your friends didn't die because they were strong.
他们死掉是因为过于虚弱
而受不了转化过程
They died because they were too weak to withstand the process.
他们的意识和身躯最终紧张到完全关闭
Their minds and bodies eventually shut down under the strain.
但是你...
But you...
你更加强壮
you're stronger.
你的强壮会证明你的破坏力
And it is your strength that will prove your undoing.
他今早上破坏了束缚器 打伤了两个守卫
He broke through his restraints this morning and injured two guards,
我认为最好把他隔离起来
so I thought it would be best to put him in isolation.
至少这样做 就算他再次逃脱
也不会伤到别人
At least this way, if he breaks free again, he won't be an immediate danger to anyone.
要多久他才能恢复过来?
How long is it going to take him to go through this?
说老实话 我都不能确定他可以恢复
To be honest, I'm not even sure he will.
拜托!
Please!
杀了我!
You're killing me!
拜托!
Please!
可以减缓他的痛苦吗?
Can't you give him something for the pain?
镇静剂可以让他舒服些 但是
Sedatives will make him more comfortable, but
也同样会减缓他的恢复
they'll also slow down his recovery.
我希望他恢复得越快越好
不要用镇定剂
I want this to go as quick as possible. No sedatives.
他睡了?
He's already sleeping?
为什么我要半天才能让他安静下来?
Why does it take so much longer when I try to put him down?
你想得太多了
You worry too much.
可能他感觉到了你的不安
Perhaps he senses your anxiety.
可能他觉得妈妈在身边更舒服
Maybe he prefers the comfort of his mother's presence.
总有一天他要自立的
Well, there may be times when he will have to learn to do without.
这是不是代表你已经做出决定了?
Does that mean you've decided?
我考虑过...
I thought so...
明知道回到小队后 每次踏过星门
就有可能回不来了
how can I return to the team with the knowledge that every time I step through the gate,
我怎能做出这个选择?
there is a chance that I might not come back?
考虑到这些危险
That, given the dangers,
有可能我们的儿子
要在没有母亲的关怀下成长
there's a possibility that our son will grow up without a mother?
你要对他负责
You have a responsibility to him.
但是你同样也要对这个星系的人民负责
But you also have a responsibility to the people of this galaxy.
只管跟随你心中的选择
不要犹豫
Follow your heart without remorse.
你要宽慰于
这样做是为了守护千万生命的未来
And take comfort in knowing that you'll be doing so to safeguard the future of many,
包括你的儿子
including your son.
答应我在战场上 时刻要小心
Just promise me you'll be careful out there.
他清醒了 据现在差不多已经10分钟了
He's been awake and lucid for about 10 minutes now.
他说了什么?
What did he say?
只想要和你对话
Only that he wanted to talk to you.
我知道他们把Ronon带到哪去了
I know where they've taken ronon.
可以提供星门的地址吗?
You can give us a gate address?
不止如此 我可以带你们到
设施的中心去
Better. I'll lead you right into the heart of the facility.
你还在恢复中
Well, you're still recovering.
Keller医生告诉我 我身体系统里的
Wraith酶已经全部消失了
Dr. Keller told me there were no longer any traces of the wraith enzyme in my system.
- 重点不是这个
- 上校 拜托
- That's not the point.
- Colonel, please.
让我帮忙把Ronon救回来
Let me help you get ronon back.
战斗中永不退缩
No retreat in the face of battle.
绝不同情失败者
No sympathy for the fallen.
对敌人毫不留情
No mercy for our enemies.
战斗中永不退缩
No retreat in the face of battle.
绝不同情失败者
No sympathy for the fallen.
对敌人毫不留情
And no mercy to your enemies.
我们的敌人
Our enemies.
Atlantis
Atlantis.
毫不留情
No mercy.
他看起来很理智
说他想帮助我们
He seems rational, says he wants to help us.
我认为只有我们
不得以的情况下才会相信他
I say we trust him only as much as we have to.
可以利用他的消息
但他得留在这被看管
Use his intel, but he stays here, under guard.
如果你想要攻击那个Warith设施
If you want to hit that wraith facility,
我们就需要所有可能的帮助
而且很显然他知道怎么进出那个地方
we'll need all the help we can get, and apparently he knows that place inside and out.
没错 所以这是个完美的引你上当的陷阱
Yes, and is thus in the perfect position to lead you right into a trap.
好吧 听着 我认为他更多希望我们相信
All right, look, I think, as much as he'd like us to believe it,
这不是为了赢回失去的荣耀
或者Satedan的复仇
this is not about regaining some lost honor, or some satedan revenge thing.
纯粹是一个绝望到不顾一切的男人
愿意做任何事情只为救回他的兄弟
Pure and simple-- this is about a desperate guy who's willing to do anything to help his buddy.
你怎么能这么肯定 上校?
And how can you be so certain of that, colonel?
因为我经历过
Because I've been there.
现在 有一个救回Ronon的机会摆在面前
我要抓住它 你必须要相信我
Now, we have a chance to get ronon, and I'm going to take it, and you're going to need to trust me on this.
好吧
All right.
Lorne少校的队伍和你一起出发
Major lorne's team will be accompanying you.
怎么了? 发生什么了?
What is it? What's happening?
我们查到Ronon在哪儿了
We know where ronon is.
我和你们一起去
I'm coming with you.
准备行动
Gear up.
呃 Teyla 我们是出于善意的决定
Uh, teyla, this is exactly the kind of decision we were--
我正要去餐厅见Kanaan
I was about to meet kanaan in the cafeteria.
你可以帮我给他解释下情况吗?
Would you please explain to him the situation?
没问题
It's all right.
拜托
Please.
好吧
All right.
乖 乖 乖
Well, well, well,
这还有谁?
who have we here?
餐厅
Cafeteria.
这边
This way.
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
你们不是要找能让炸药发挥
最大威力的地方么?
You were looking for a target area that would maximize the effects of your explosives.
就是这儿了 这个设施的能量中转舱
Well, this is it, the facility's power relay cham R.
把炸药藏好 别让他们发现了
Hide your charges to avoid discovery.
我们走
Let's go.
我猜你肯定有能够远程引爆的方法
I assume you have a means to remote-detonate from a safe distance?
当然 掀开保险
Well, just flip...
按这个
click.
这边
This way.
Ronon
Ronon.
Sheppard
Sheppard.
来的正是时候
It's about time.
发生什么了 伙计?
What's going on, buddy?
我们还以为你们不会来了呢
We were beginning to wonder if you'd ever show up.
你们的力量已经处于下风
You're at a disadvantage.
想逃走也可以 不过这样
你们朋友的小命就保不住了
You could attempt an escape, but you'll have to sacrifice your friend's life to do so.
Ronon 快让开
Ronon, get out of the way.
办不到
I can't do that.
Ronon 让开
Ronon, step aside.
会送命的不只是他一个
His life wouldn't be the only one forfeit.
Tyre...
放下武器
lower your weapons.
把他们带下去
Take them away.
Ronon 到底是怎么回事?
Ronon, what's happening here?
Ronon!
这个价码可以换回你的奖赏了吧?
I assume this is a prize worthy of reward?
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
噢
Well, you know,
从好的方面讲 我们不用回Atlantis
听Woolsey唠叨 "早跟你们说过"
on the bright side, at least we'll never have to go back to atlantis and hear woolsey say "I told you so."
我们会离开这里的
We're going to get out of here.
噢 当然 我们要做的
只是从这个牢房逃走 是吧?
Oh, sure, all we have to do is escape from this cell, right?
然后从全副武装的Wraith卫兵身边溜走
I mean, get past all of the armed wraith that are guarding the facility
另外还要去把Lorne和他的人解救出来
逃回到Jumper飞船那里
and free lorne and his team from wherever they're being held, get back to the jumper,
在我们说话这会 可能早就被拆掉了
哦 当然
which is probably being disassembled as we speak, and of course
我们还要去解救Ronon 不知道你们
注意到没有 他像是变了一个人似的
we've got to rescue ronon who, I don't know if you happened to notice or not, isn't quite himself.
我们会救出Ronon 并返回Atlantis的
We're going to get ronon and we're going to go back to atlantis.
即便我们做到了 然后呢 嗯?
And even if we do, then what, huh?
Tyre的恢复情况
并没有我们想象中的那么成功
Tyre's recovery hasn't exactly been the rousing success we were hoping for.
我们一定要救出Ronon
We're going to get ronon back.
是的 当然
Yeah. Of course.
我们要救他出来
We're going to get him back.
杀了他们你就浪费了一个极好机会
You waste a huge opportunity by killing them.
要不是他们知道的那些信息
这些人对我来说一点用都没有
They have no use to me beyond the information they can provide.
你低估了他们的价值
You underestimate their value
到底是我低估了他们的价值
还是高估了你对我的忠诚?
Is it their value I underestimate, or your loyalty I overestimate?
Ronon说得没错
Ronon's right.
让他们活着并跟你合作
对你来说利用价值更高
They're much more useful to you alive and cooperative.
只需要好好开导开导
They just need some convincing.
有办法了
All right, I've got it.
跟他们说 我们有些重要的信息
We tell them we have some vital information that we're willing to give up,
不过只会告诉Ronon一个人
but we will only share it with ronon.
他们派Ronon过来 等他出现后
我们请求他...
So they send ronon, he shows up, we appeal to him--
我是说 他还没有完全变坏
I mean, the part of him that's still him.
你的这个方案里我只想出三个缺陷
接着讲吧
Well, I can only think of three things wrong with that plan, but go on.
他被洗脑的时间没有Tyre长
也许更容易受到我们的影响
He hasn't been brainwashed as long as tyre, which means he might be more susceptible to our influence.
我们可以说服他放了我们 或带我们出去
We convince him to let us out or lead us out of here, and then,
即便做最坏的打算
我们没能完全说服他...
worst-case scenario, he's not entirely convinced--
这就是你估计的最坏的打算?
that's your worst-case scenario?
我也没有想好 不过
Hey, I'm just spinning here, but,
我们可以利用当时不确定性
然后 然后...
you know, we could take advantage of that moment of uncertainty and-- and--
Sheppard
Sheppard.
他要见你
You've been summoned.
要再复习一下我们的计划么?
Do you want to, uh, go over the plan one more time?
不 我想我能应付
No. No, I think I'm good.
看来轮到我上肉案子了
I guess it's my turn for the sales pitch, huh?
等等
Wait.
我们要去取点东西
We need to get something.
跪下
Kneel.
真有意思 你怎么不跪呢?
You know what would be really creepy and unexpected, is if you knelt instead.
老天啊...
God...
我想你是不会吧
I guess not.
那好吧 我会尽力帮你
All right, I'll try and make it work.
我很欣赏你的桀骜不驯
I appreciate your defiance.
Ronon 真希望你能快点醒来
Ronon, I really need you to snap out of it about now.
这会让转变你的过程更有乐趣
It will make turning you all the more enjoyable.
Teyla! Mckay! 你们是怎么出来的?
Teyla! Mckay! How'd you get out?
Tyre 放我们出来的 快走
Tyre freed us. Let's go.
OK 快点 伙计们
Okay, come on, guys.
快 快 快!
Go, go, go!
情况怎样?
How's it going?
不是很好!
Not so good!
我的人正挡着他们 不过撑不了多久了
My guys are holding them off, but not for much longer.
把这个给我
Give me that.
命令他们撤退
Tell them to back off.
相对于你和你的队员们来说
My life will be a small price to pay
我这条小命算不了什么
for the lives of you and your team.
那如果我们炸掉这整个设施呢?
Then how about the destruction of this facility?
是不是也算不了什么?
Is that a small enough price as well?
你骗人
You lie.
我告诉过他们 把炸药埋在哪里
可以发挥最大威力
I told them where to hide the charges for maximum effect,
足以炸掉这整个设施
包括所有研究成果
enough explosives to destroy this place and all of its research.
所有你们取得的领先成果
Any advantage your hive may hold over its rivals
在我按下这个按钮后
就都将灰飞烟灭
will be gone with the push of a button.
等等!
Wait!
跟他们说 放我们过去
Tell them to let us through.
怎么保证你们跑远后 不会按下那个按钮
What's to stop you from triggering the explosives from a safe distance?
我留下
My presence here.
放他们走 我留下
You let them go. I'll remain behind.
- Tyre...
- 等他们到星门那里后
- once they've reached the gate,
我会用这个装置
来换取我自己的自由
I'll trade you this device for my freedom.
再不走我们就都会死在这里
Or we all die together.
放他们走
Let them go.
我稍后就会跟上
I'll be right behind you.
我们走
Let's go.
你这样做等于是放弃了一份
难以想象的大礼
You turn your back on an incredible gift.
事实上 是你首先抛弃我的
Actually, you turned your back on me first.
我还没好好感谢你呢
And I thank you for it.
我们出来了
We're clear.
我可以宽恕你
You're not beyond forgiveness.
现在还不是太晚
It's not too late for you.
不 已经太迟了...
Yes, it is...
对我们双方而言
for both of us.
恢复周期大概需要多长?
What kind of a timeframe for recovery are we looking at?
很难估计
It's impossible to predict.
他体内的酶素太多
几乎超过了机体能承受的极限
He has so much of the enzyme running through him that his body can hardly process it.
在机体代谢完这些酶后
When it eventually does,
他就会安静下来
that's when he'll come down,
而这是个艰巨的过程
and he'll come down hard.
我要去跟他谈谈
I'm going to talk to him.
打开
Open it.
看谁来了
There he is.
嘿 伙计
Hey, buddy.
伙计
Buddy.
你还准备把我关多久?
So, how long are you planning on keeping me prisoner?
在你头脑彻底清醒之后
As long as it takes to clear your head.
我的头脑很清醒
My head is clear.
你现在可能感觉很好 不过
Well, you may be feeling fine right now, but
这一过程对你来说可能会非常痛苦
things are going to get pretty rough for you.
我们会一直陪伴你的
We're going to get you through this.
不管你打的是什么主意
都不会奏效的
Whatever you've got planned, it's not going to work.
你有两个选择
You've got a choice--
要么杀了我 要么就放我走
you'd better kill me or you let me go.
如果放我走 我保证不会再来
找你和Atlantis的麻烦
And if you let me go, I promise I won't come after you or atlantis.
跟Tyre说 我也不会去找他的麻烦
Tell tyre I won't come after him either.
Tyre死了
Tyre's dead.
他牺牲了自己 炸掉了Wraith的实验室
He sacrificed himself taking out the wraith lab.
这个叛徒
Yeah, well, he was a traitor.
不 他是我们的好朋友
No, he was a good friend.
我们都是好朋友
We all are.
你很快就会意识到这一点的
You're going to realize that pretty soon.
嘿 你要么杀了我 要么就放我走
Hey, will you just kill me or set me free.
Sheppard!
杀了我 或者放我走!
You kill me or set me free!
Sheppard!
杀了我吧!
Kill me please!
求你们了!
Please kill me!
不!
No!
我拥有他们所称之为的钢琴指
纤细 灵巧
I had what they called piano fingers-- slim, nimble.
难怪我父母给我报了钢琴课
It's really no surprise that my parents signed me up for lessons.
我的首任老师 跟往常一样
向我打招呼
My first teacher, of course, hailed me as a natural.
一个俄国女人 忘了她是叫
普兰斯基还是巴兰斯基
Big russian woman, polanskii or baranski or...
Sheppard...
sheppard...
反正是个什么"斯基"
definitely a "ski".
Ronon?
感觉怎样?
Hey, uh, how do you feel?
感觉想打人
Like hitting someone.
选好对象了没?
Anyone in particular?
你 如果你不给我松绑
并给我带点吃的过来的话
You, if you don't loosen these straps and get me something to eat.
这是个好兆头
That is a good sign.
这是个好兆头!
That's a good sign!
他好了! 他好了!
He's back! He's back!
这么说他已经完全恢复了?
So he's fully recovered?
他的身体仍很虚弱
Well, physically he's still weak,
不过血液检查显示 他体内
已经没有酶素了
but his bloodwork shows no traces of the enzyme in his system, so
不用多久 他就能恢复原样
he should be back to his old self in no time.
真是好消息
Good to hear.
好了 很晚了
Well, it's late.
我要回房间 换一身休闲一点的衣服
I think I'll head back to my quarters and change into something a little more relaxed.
晚安
Good night.
John 能和你谈谈么?
John, may I have a word?
当然
Yeah. Sure.
Teyla 请进
Teyla. Come in.
你不是说过换一身休闲一点的衣服
I thought you said you were changing into something more relaxed.
对我来说 这就是休闲服
For me, this is more relaxed.
- 想来一杯么?
- 不 谢了
- Can I offer you a drink?
- No, thank you.
我和John谈过了
现在想获得正式的批准
I just spoke with john, and now I would like to make it official.
希望能让我立即归队
I'm requesting a return to active duty.
回到Sheppard中校所在小队中的位置
I would like to resume my position on colonel sheppard's team.
你确信要这么做?
You're sure this is what you want?
非常希望
Very much so.
那好吧 欢迎归队
Well, then, welcome back.
谢谢 Woolsey先生
Thank you, mr. Woolsey.
- 晚安
- Good night.